cocoacasts.com 2019-01-07

# Privacy Policy

## The Privacy Policy was last updated on **May 25, 2018**.

Cocoacasts is a product of Code Foundry BVBA. Your privacy is critically important to us. At Code Foundry BVBA, we have a few fundamental principles. (i) We don't ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (ii) We don't share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights. (iii) We don't store personal information on our servers unless required for the ongoing operation of one of our services.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates these goals. If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please contact us.

Code Foundry BVBA ("Code Foundry") operates several websites and applications, including Cocoacasts. It is Code Foundry's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our products.

## Website Visitors and Product Usage

Like most product businesses, Code Foundry collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Code Foundry's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Code Foundry's customers use its websites and products. From time to time, Code Foundry may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, for example, by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its websites and products.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to cocoacasts.com choose to interact with cocoacasts.com in ways that require cocoacasts.com to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that cocoacasts.com gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for Cocoacasts Plus for their name, email address, and physical address.

In each case, cocoacasts.com collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with cocoacasts.com. Cocoacasts.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities, like signing up for Cocoacasts Plus.

All of the information that is collected on cocoacasts.com will be handled in accordance with GDPR legislation.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Code Foundry discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Code Foundry's behalf or to provide Code Foundry's services or products, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Code Foundry's websites and products, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Code Foundry will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and non-personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Code Foundry discloses potentially personally-identifying and non-personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Code Foundry believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Code Foundry, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of a Code Foundry website or product and have supplied your email address, Code Foundry may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with Code Foundry and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Code Foundry takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and non-personally-identifying information.

## Use of Personal Information

We will not sell or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

We would like to send you email marketing communication which may be of interest to you from time to time. If you have consented to marketing, you may opt out later.

You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. If you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every email we send you.

## Legal Grounds for Processing Personal Information

We rely on one or more of the following processing conditions: (i) our legitimate interests in the effective delivery of information and services to you; (ii) explicit consent that you have given; (iii) legal obligations.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Code Foundry uses cookies to help Code Foundry identify and track visitors, their usage of the Code Foundry websites, and their website access preferences. Code Foundry visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Code Foundry's websites, with the drawback that certain features of Code Foundry's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## Access to Data

You have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all your personal information, please follow the instructions at the end of this policy.

Cocoacasts.com user accounts can be edited by following these steps: (i) Visit https://cocoacasts.com/signin and enter your email address and password. (ii) Click your name in the top right and choose 'Profile' or 'Account' to enter you personal information.

## Retention of Personal Information

We will retain your personal information on our systems only for as long as we need to, for the success of of the Cocoacasts platform. We keep contact information (such as mailing list information) until a user unsubscribes or requests that we delete that information from our live systems. If you choose to unsubscribe from a mailing list, we may keep certain limited information about you so that we may honor your request.

Cocoacasts.com will not delete personal data from logs or records necessary to the operation, development, or archives of the Cocoacasts platform."

## Rights in Relation to Your Information

You may have certain rights under data protection law in relation to the personal information we hold about you. In particular, you may have a right to: (i) request a copy of personal information we hold about you; (ii) ask that we update the personal information we hold about you, or independently correct such personal information that you think is incorrect or incomplete; (iii) ask that we delete personal information that we hold about you from live systems, or restrict the way in which we use such personal information (for information on deletion from archives, see the 'Retention of Personal Information' section); (iv) object to our processing of your personal information; and/or (v) withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal information (to the extent such processing is based on consent and consent is the only permissible basis for processing).

If you would like to exercise these rights or understand if these rights apply to you, please follow the instructions at the end of this Privacy Policy.

## Third Party Services

Cocoacasts.com relies on a number of third paryt services to function. Each of these companies fully complies with GDPR. This is a listing of these third parties. (i) We use [Heroku](https://www.heroku.com/) to store data from Cocoacasts Plus subscribers. (ii) [Chargebee](https://www.chargebee.com/) is used for handling Cocoacasts Plus subscriptions. (iii) We use [Postmark](https://postmarkapp.com/) to send transaction email. (iv) Customer support is handled by [Help Scout](https://www.helpscout.net/). (v) We use [Drip](https://www.drip.com/) and [OptinMonster](https://optinmonster.com/) for email marketing communication. (vi) [Algolia](https://www.algolia.com/) powers search on Cocoacasts.com. (vii) We use [Leanpub](https://leanpub.com/) and [Gumroad](https://gumroad.com/) for selling the books published by Cocoacasts. (viii) Payments are handled by [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/), [Chargebee](https://www.chargebee.com/), [Leanpub](https://leanpub.com/), and [Gumroad](https://gumroad.com/).

## Third Party Links

Our website may contain links to other websites provided by third parties not under our control. When following a link and providing information to a third party website, please be aware that we are not responsible for the data provided to that third party. This Privacy Policy only applies to cocoacasts.com, so when you visit other websites, even when you click on a link posted on cocoacasts.com, you should read their own privacy policies.

## Aggregated Statistics

Cocoacasts.com may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. However, cocoacasts.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Business Transfers

If Code Foundry, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Code Foundry goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Code Foundry may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## Payment Information

Payment information, such as credit card and debit card details, are never handled directly by Code Foundry. We partner with [Stripe](https://stripe.com/), [Chargebee](https://chargebee.com/), [Leanpub](https://leanpub.com/), and [Gumroad](https://gumroad.com/) to distribute our products and services. These companies take security and safety very seriously. Each of these companies fully complies with GDPR. Code Foundry never stores your payment details on its servers.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Code Foundry may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Code Foundry's sole discretion. Code Foundry encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this website and our products after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

The Privacy Policy was last updated on May 25, 2018. The Privacy Policy is inspired by [Automattic’s Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/), which is made available under a [Creative Commons ShareAlike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) license.

## Contact Us

Please contact us if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or information we hold about you by emailing support@cocoacasts.com.
